{
    "id": "81e5f7bfa3af48d598c64db754de7b0a",
    "title": "Modals Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He is the chief guest. He ………………………………… to be here on time.",
            "description": "Ought is followed by a to-infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "should",
                "must",
                "ought"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………… you lend me a few hundred dollars?",
            "description": "Either can or could is possible here. Could is more polite than can.",
            "answers": [
                "Can",
                "Could",
                "May",
                "Must"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It is dangerous to go out alone at night. You ………………………….. never do it.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "could",
                "should",
                "shall"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you start in the morning, you ……………………………. reach there by evening.",
            "description": "Will is more appropriate here. In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + bare infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "could"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "They sell the best pizza in town. You …………………………… definitely try it.",
            "description": "Should is often used to give advice. ",
            "answers": [
                "should",
                "would",
                "could"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If it rains, we ………………………………. get wet.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "could"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If she spoke a little French, she ……………………………. find a better job.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + bare infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "can",
                "could"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………………………….. be an introvert during his university days.",
            "description": "Used to can be used to talk about past states. ",
            "answers": [
                "should",
                "would",
                "used to"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………………… you like to come with me?",
            "description": "Would is used in polite offers. ",
            "answers": [
                "Could",
                "Would",
                "Should"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We …………………………. never throw away anything useful.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "should",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I can’t find my phone. I …………………………………… have lost it on the bus.",
            "description": "All of these are possible here with slight differences in meaning. ",
            "answers": [
                "could",
                "might",
                "must",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Where .................................... she have gone?",
            "description": "Either can or could is possible here. ",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could",
                "may",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}